# Jacqueline Calapristi

509.438.8887 • jackie.lc11@gmail.com • www.JackieCalapristi.com

### Skills

Experienced software engineer with a history in startups, consulting, education, sustainable solutions & working across the stack. I have a track record of diving into completely unfamiliar codebases, learning quickly & adding value right away. Building software that is changing the world alongside passionate people is what I love to do.

#### Professional

- JavaScript
- React, ReactNative
- Redux
- Typescript
- Jest, Karma, Mocha
  Storybook
  PHP with Yii
  Git, GitHub
  AWS, Azure
  Puppeteer
  SQL, MySQL
  Docker

- Ruby on Rails
- RSpec
- C#.NET
- Node

- Machine Learning
- MVC, MVVM
- Agile, Waterfall
- Splunk, Elasticsearch

#### Personal

- Python
- Java

- Express
- Heroku
- MongoDB
- Postgres

## Experience

# Software Engineer | Luum

Mar 2019 - Present • Seattle, WA

- Developed Subsidy Management, Pre-Tax Commuter Benefits & Note Management platforms responsible for correctly distributing commute-based subsidies and benefits to 500K+ employees daily at multiple Fortune 50 companies. These platforms directly incentivize employees to pick sustainable commute options that lower their carbon footprints, decrease traffic & save employers money.
- Oversaw new mobile ReactNative codebase including offering guidance on high level approaches, architectural choices & component organization.
- Introduced tech design best practices & document templates to streamline development flow & prevent tech design flaws before building features.
- Replaced legacy version control (team foundation services) with Git & trained multiple senior engineers new to Git on their new workflows.

#### Software Development Engineer || | 10.000ft

Nov 2017 – Feb 2019 • Seattle, WA • Acquired by SmartSheet

- Implemented powerful project management interface with collapsing, filtering, sorting & CRUD functionalities utilizing React, Redux & Ruby on Rails. Our data suggests that this feature was the main driving force for our company's ability to increase ARR 30% in one year.
- Designed à la carte ABAC permission system & implementation plan to replace our previous permission system that was based on static roles.
- Built new signup page in React with simpler UI/UX design that has contributed to a higher lead conversion rate.
- Created 10K Day (similar to innovation day) program & team goal setting program which has generated 10+ new features within our application.
- Trained junior engineers & interviewed promising applicants.

# **Software Development Engineer** | Conversica, Inc.

- Built robust & eye-catching UIs with JavaScript, Angular, PHP & Yii for machine learning/AI SaaS startup.
- Managed in-house KPI report generation application used by top level management for meetings with key investors.
- Incorporated continuous improvements into our OLAP system, Rules Engine, Leads API & Analytics API.
- Implemented & maintained cron jobs vital for our Finance, Customer Success & Engineering Systems to sync dependent data correctly around the clock.
- Developed key features within our internal dashboard, integrations dashboard & appointment system.

# **Software Developer** | Vitech Business Group, Inc.

July 2013 - March 2015 \* Bellingham, WA \* Acquired by HighJump

- Designed & launched custom warehouse systems & web applications using SQL stored procedures & HighJump software.
- Traveled frequently on-site to implement & showcase our work live in front of clients.
- Supported production systems with 100+ end users.

# UI/UX Design Intern | POS-X

Apr 2013 - June 2013 • Bellingham, WA

Information Systems Intern | U.S. Department of Energy Contractor June 2012 - Sept 2012 • Richland, WA

#### **Patents**

# Application No. 16/228,723 | US Patent Office

Filed Dec 20, 2018 • Systems and methods for improving user engagement in machine learning conversation management using gamification

## Volunteering

## AP Computer Science Teaching Assistant | Microsoft Philanthropy

June 2016 – June 2017 \* Sehome High School \* Bellingham, WA

- Assisted in teaching university level AP Computer Science to high school students twice a week in the mornings before work.
- Trained at Microsoft's campus in Java, teaching methods & techniques.

## Public Speaking

# Software Development In The Wild

WWU MIS Department • 2014 – Present (Quarterly)

Machine Learning Panelist
Western IS Connection • April 2018

## **OLAP for Cheesemakers**

Bellingham.Codes • July 2016

Let's Build Robots!
Girl Scouts • July 2016

### Education

## Management Information Systems (MIS) | WWU

B.A. in Business Administration • June 2013 • Bellingham, WA

## E-Commerce Web Development Certificate | WWU

Jan 2012 – June 2013 • Bellingham, WA

## Machine Learning Foundations | University of Washington

Dec 2016 - Jan 2017 • Seattle, WA